Finding Aid for Latin Americans for Social and Economic Development Records, 1969-97
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Latin Americans for Social and Economic Development Records 1969-97
Latin Americans for Social and Economic Development
1 linear ft.
9816-Bd 2
Latino social service organization active in southwest Detroit, Michigan; records, primarily assembled by board member Lucy Gajec, include administrative files, correspondence, and publicity material,
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The record group was donated by Dr. Lucile Gajec (donor no. 8528 ) and came to the library in 1997.
The collection is open for research.
Latin Americans for Social and Economic Development (LASED) is a social service organization which serves the Latino community of Detroit, particularly the heavily Latino neighborhoods of Southwest Detroit. The organization's acronym also means "the thirst" in Spanish, and is usually written and pronounced as two words. LASED was founded in 1969 through the cooperative efforts of community leaders, union officials, and the Catholic Archdiocese of Detroit. Since then, LASED has provided a wide variety of bilingual services to its constituent community, including advocacy, information services, referrals, and translation. The organization also operates two special centers. The LASED Youth Center provides counseling and advocacy services, youth employment programs, and recreational activities for young people. The LASED Senior Citizen's Center provides social services for the elderly. LASED is funded by United Community Services, the City of Detroit, individual donors, and private foundations.
The record of Latin Americans for Social and Economic Development are arranged in four series:
Chronological
Topical Files
Publications
Photographs
The LASED records consists of material accumulated by Lucy Gajec, a member of the LASED board of directors. The records, primarily official documents, rather than personal correspondence, are divided into four series.
Subjects:
Latin Americans for Social and Economic Development; Hispanic Americans--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.)
- Chronological Files
  The Chronological (1969-1997) series contains correspondence, memos, event publicity, legal and financial documents, and clippings concerning LASED
  - 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - 1969-1972 (Box 1)
  - 1972, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 1973 (Box 1)
  - 1974, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1975 (Box 1)
  - 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - 1995-1997 (Box 1)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files (1971-1974) contain correspondence, memos, and printed material concerning a variety of subjects relevant to the activities and operation of LASED.
  - Budget, 1971-72 (Box 1)
  - By-laws, Undated (Box 1)
  - Community Task Force; Television and Radio Material, 1974-75 (Box 1)
  - Developmental Disabilities Program
    - 1973-75 (Box 1)
    - 1973-76 (Box 1)
  - Educational Task Force, 1973-74, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Grant Proposals, 1973, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Latino Revenue Sharing, 1973 (Box 1)
- Publications
  The Publications series contains one folder of miscellaneous pamphlets and programs about LASED, and one folder of programs from the organization's Annual Recognition Luncheons (1969-1997).
  - General Publications, 1970-1991 (Box 1)
  - Annual Recognition Luncheon Programs, 1992-1997 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  The Photograph series consists of one photograph of Lucy Gajec.
  - Lucy Gajec portrait, undated (Box 1)